{
    "id": "35215d9764be4ddaa166bef75365b986",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He was Catholic, …………………….. most of his friends.",
            "description": "As is sometimes followed by auxiliary verb + subject.",
            "answers": [
                "were as",
                "as were",
                "and were"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bef43c92791d4a1db5a34f30f77c6887"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1939, …………………………. in 1914, everybody wanted war.",
            "description": "As is a conjunction. It can be used before an expression beginning with a preposition.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bc244a063acd44f8b0149015c72ce8e3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I never enjoyed ……………………………",
            "description": "When life refers to a particular way of living, it is usually uncountable.",
            "answers": [
                "a city life",
                "the city life",
                "city life"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3a2bf97d82bb4a66abd058f9b5bdf8fc"
        },
        {
            "question": "They kept watch all night, ………………………. robbers should come.",
            "description": "Lest is similar to in case.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "lest",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6f589a94ed53456c98806019f876d6e1"
        },
        {
            "question": "There are ……………………… if you are hungry.",
            "description": "Left goes at the end of the structure.",
            "answers": [
                "left two bananas",
                "two bananas left",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "da92f68a4142442595b37ca04909006b"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………. cook their own food these days.",
            "description": "Before nouns without determiners (articles, possessives etc.), we use fewer without of.",
            "answers": [
                "Fewer people",
                "Fewer of people",
                "less people"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "516fc846865e459fa8052e726d53a522"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would like to spend ……………………….. my time doing laundry.",
            "description": "We use less of before a noun with a determiner.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "less of",
                "fewer"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e844244789374192a91c177c6d58f65a"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. have been quite stressful.",
            "description": "We generally use ‘the last few days’, not ‘last few days’.",
            "answers": [
                "Last few days",
                "The last few days"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f36538aa804246b1a9cf747d76a5b2c7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you enjoy your ………………………….. job?",
            "description": "We use latest to refer to very recent things.",
            "answers": [
                "last",
                "latest",
                "later"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "da232905c6fa4adab2b552a1de95ca55"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the last letter he …………………………. from me.",
            "description": "Both present and future tenses are possible after ‘this is the last ….’",
            "answers": [
                "gets",
                "will get",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fe394c555cec45c5803983ee741f2967"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know …………………………?",
            "description": "Know cannot be followed directly by an infinitive. We use ‘know how to’.",
            "answers": [
                "to swim",
                "how to swim"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bb9564730360454bbeec101652eb1412"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am tired. It is time we …………………….. home",
            "description": "After ‘it is time’ we use a past tense with a present meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "have gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "018befe3958c4623956d63a6b4dbd9ef"
        }
    ]
}